Guide to the Everett Cherrington Hughes Papers 1922-1982
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Writings and Research Material
  - Subseries 2: Research Materials
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, manuscripts, 1970 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, notes, newspaper clippings, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, John Donovan, Life and ministry description, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, Sally Cassidy, Life and ministry, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, Special Priestly Problems, Sally Cassidy and John Donovan, a. Authority and Anomie, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, Special Priestly Problems, b. Celibacy, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, Special Priestly Problems, c. Laity, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, Special Priestly Problems, d. Age, manuscripts and Hughes, memoranda, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, Special Priestly Problems, e. The Priest's Work, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, Special Priestly Problems, f. Spirituality, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, "Introduction," 1971 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, "Conclusion," report draft, 1970, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - American Priest Study, National Opinion Research Center, "An Evaluation of `American Priests, A Report of the National Opinion Research Center,'" prepared for the United States Catholic Conference by Hughes, Cassidy and Donovan, July 15, 1971 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - American Priestly Study, miscellaneous manuscript, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 15-16)
  - Subseries 3: Note Cards, ca. 1920s-1930s
    - Item 1: Industry and the community (Box 105)
    - Item 2: Crowd and public (Box 105)
    - Item 3: Pullman and other model communities (Box 105)
    - Item 4: Social institutions (Box 105)
    - Item 5: History of anthropology (Box 105)
    - Item 6: Durkheim (Box 105)
    - Item 7: Social psychology (Box 105)
    - Item 8: Survey (Box 105)
    - Item 9: Economic manias (Box 105)
    - Item 10: Miscellaneous (Box 105)
    - Item 1: Miscellaneous class and seminar notes (Box 106)
    - Item 2: French Canada (Box 106)
    - Item 1: Miscellaneous (Box 107)
  - Subseries 4: Translations
    - Durkheim, Emile, Division of Labor in Society, preface to second edition, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Maunier, Rene, "The Diffusion of French Law in Algeria," in Independence, Convergence and Borrowing in Institutions, Thought and Art, 1937 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Mendes-France, P., "After the Congo, the Mali. All of Black Africa Is on the Boil," L'Express, August 25, 1960 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Schmid, M., Verfassung und Verwaltung der Deutschen Stadte, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Simmel, Georg, lecture, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Sombart, Werner, "The New Spirits," Chapter VII of Das Wirtschaftsleben Im Aeitalter Des Hochkapitalismus, Chapter VII, manuscript, 1927, typescript, 1976 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Weber, Max, "Max Weber's Proposal for Sociological Study of Voluntary Associations ("Gesch‰ftsbericht"), 1940 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 5: Book Reviews
    - Authors A-L, 1926-1949 (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Authors M-Y, 1926-1949 (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - 1953-1963 (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - 1964-1969, 1979 (Box 108, Folder 11)
    - Mayer, Martin, The Lawyers, 1968 (Box 108, Folder 12)
    - Patterson, Orlando, Ethnic Chauvinism, The Reactionary Impulse, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 13)
    - Servan-Schreiber, Jean-Jacques, Le DÈfi Americain, 1968 (Box 108, Folder 14)
    - Weber, Marianne, Max Weber: The Biography, translated from the German and edited by Harry Zohn, notes and lecture notes on Max Weber, 1976-1978 (Box 108, Folder 15)
    - Comments from others on review of Marianne Weber's Max Weber: A Biography, 1976 (Box 108, Folder 16)
    - A History of Sociological Analysis, eds. Tom Bottomore & Robert Nisbett, 1979 (Box 108, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 6: Manuscripts
    - List of unpublished manuscripts by Hughes, 1970 (Box 108, Folder 18)
    - "Human Ecology," 1926 (Box 108, Folder 19)
    - Special articles and lectures, list, manuscripts, 1926-1961 (Box 108, Folder 20-21)
    - Action Catholique, memoranda, notes, 1942-1943, 1974 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Park, Robert, memorial service, eulogies, 1944 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Sketches for general articles, 1944-1948, 1963 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - "Good People and Dirty Work," 1948-1963 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Race, unpublished manuscripts, lectures, 1948-1964 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Race and Culture: A Collection of The Writings of Robert E. Park, book contract, 1949 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, Volumes 1-3, reviews, 1952-1956 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, correspondence, 1949 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, correspondence, 1950 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, correspondence, 1951 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, correspondence, 1952 (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, correspondence, 1954 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 109, Folder 13)
    - Collection of the Writings of Robert E. Park, manuscript material, 1951-1954 (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - Work, "Routine and Emergency," lecture, notes, 1950 (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - "Bastard Institutions," lecture, November 26, 1951 (Box 109, Folder 16)
    - "Two Worlds," one act play, 1951 (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - "The Natural History of a Research Project: French Canada," paper, Society of Applied Anthropology, 1952 (Box 109, Folder 18)
    - "The Social Drama of Work," lecture, University of Kansas, December 4, 1952 (Box 109, Folder 19)
    - Education, manuscripts, lectures, 1952-1966 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Careers, unpublished manuscripts, lectures, notes, 1952-1967 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - "Professional and Career Problems of Sociology," International Sociological Association, Liège Congress, August 24-September 1, 1953 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - "Work Careers," report to the Work Conference, Kansas City Study of Adult Life, October 15, 1954 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Address, Naturalization Session, Conference on Race Relations, Honolulu, June 24, 1954 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - "Selectivity and Discrimination in American Education or the New Equality," National Intercollegiate Conference on Selectivity and Discrimination in American Universities, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, March 26, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - "Nature of Racial Frontiers," dedication of Park Hall, Fisk University, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - "Improper Study of Man," 1955 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Address, inauguration of Dr. Samuel C. Kincheloe as President of Tougaloo Southern Christian College, October 20, 1956 (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - "Occupations," 1957 (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - "Going Concerns: The Study of American Institutions," American Sociological Association, Washington, D. C., 1957 (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - American sociology, essays, 1958-1961 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Lipset-Riesman paper, 1959 (Box 110, Folder 13)
    - "Redfield Lecture," Anthropology 241, January 16, 1959 (Box 110, Folder 14)
    - "Age of the Consumer," ca. 1960 (Box 110, Folder 15)
    - "Quizzes and Licence," comment on the radio quiz scandal, 1960 (Box 110, Folder 16)
    - "Jane Addams Centennial," address, Delaware, Ohio, April 30, 1960 (Box 110, Folder 17)
    - Conference on Career Opportunities in Criminal Justice, Harvard Law School, July 17-21, 1961 (Box 110, Folder 18)
    - "Tarde's Psychologie ...conomique: An Unknown Classic by a Forgotten Sociologist," manuscript, notes, 1961 (Box 110, Folder 19)
    - "Going Concerns," Howard University lectures, correspondence, 1962 (Box 110, Folder 20)
    - E. Franklin Frazier, addresses and lectures about, 1962 (Box 110, Folder 21)
    - "The Negro in American Society," lecture, New School of New York, November 19, 1962 (Box 110, Folder 22)
    - "Talk Given to Freshman Seminars," Spring 1962 (Box 110, Folder 23)
    - "Race Relations and the Sociological Imagination," Presidential Address to the American Sociological Association, 1963 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - "Race Relations and the Sociological Imagination," Presidential Address to the American Sociological Association, correspondence, 1963 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - "Individual Belligerency and Collective Belligerency," American Sociological Association, Washington, D.C., August 1962, memorandum, 1963 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - "Desires and Needs of Society," American Medical Association, 59th Annual Congress on Medical Education, February 3-4, 1963 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - "Education and Culture of the Majority," Symposium on Library Functions in the Changing Metropolis, May 27-29, 1963 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - "Is Education a Discipline?" 1963 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - "Language and Society," Research Seminar on Sociolinguistics, Committee on Sociolinguistics of the Social Science Research Council, 1964 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - "Paper on Canadian-American Relations Written for American Assembly, 1964" (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - "French-Canada Still in Transition," lectures 1-3, 1965 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Professional Ethics in Time of Change," American Medical Association National Conference on Medical Ethics, March 4-5, 1966 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - "Are the Clergy a Profession?" in The Church and Its Manpower Management, A Report of the First National Consultation on Church Personnel Policies and Practices, eds. Ross P. Scherer and Theodore O. Wedel, National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., 1966 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - "Careers in Advanced Industrial Societies," International Congress of Psychology, Moscow, August 4-11, 1966 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - "The Passing of the Dual Society," notes on talk at the University of Mississippi, 1966 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - "A Policeman's Lot Is Not a Happy One," August 7, 1966 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - "Work and Leisure in Modern Society," Voice of America lecture, correspondence, notes, 1966-1967 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - "Race and Language," lecture, Florida State University, January 19, 1967 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - "Ernest Watson Burgess: The First Young Sociologist," January 1967 (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - "Regionalism in French-Canada," Centennial Seminar, UniversitÇ Laval, August 20-25, 1967 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - "Quebec and the American Challenge," 1968 (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - "de Gaulle in Quebec: The Happening, the Word and the Exegesis," 1968 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - "Involvement and Detachment," "Disjunction and Continuity," Siena Conference, Memphis, March 29-30, 1968 (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - "Is America by Nature a Violent Society?" draft, notes, 1963-1968 (Box 111, Folder 22)
    - "The Growth of an Institution: The Chicago Real Estate Board," author's note, 1969 (Box 111, Folder 23)
    - "The Humble and the Proud: The Comparative Study of Occupations," lecture, 1969 (Box 111, Folder 24)
    - "The Sociological Enterprise in Canada," Convocation speech, Queen's University, May 1969 (Box 111, Folder 25)
    - Selected papers of Everett C. Hughes, table of contents, 1970 (Box 111, Folder 26)
    - Selected papers of Everett C. Hughes, notes, 1970 (Box 111, Folder 27)
    - The Sociological Eye, preface, 1970 (Box 111, Folder 28)
    - "Robert E. Park," The Dictionary of American Biography, manuscript, correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - "The Linguistic Division of Labor in Industrial and Urban Society," 1970 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - McGill University convocation address, correspondence, memoranda, notes, June 5, 1970 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - "Discrimination and Parity," February 1970 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - "Otakar Machotka," eulogy, August 10, 1970 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - "Women and Men," colloquium, Northwestern University, March 4, 1971 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - "Higher Education and the Professions," second revised copy, Boston College, Sociology Department, September 1971 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - "RenÈ LÈvesque and the Quebec Independence Movement," June 16, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - "Colonies, Colonization, and Colonialism," notes, bibliography, correspondence, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - "Neo-Feminism, an Essay on Woman's Work," essay, correspondence, memoranda, notes, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Obituaries, 1973-1979 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - "Remarks to Be Made at the Retirement Dinner in Honor of Oswald Hall," correspondence, 1974 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Heinrich Bˆll, notes, bibliography, memoranda, 1974-1979 (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Rudolf Heberle, memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - "Problems in the Sociology of Work," Society for the Study of Social Problems, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - "Introducing Howard S. Becker," March 14, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - "Notes on the Teaching of Sociology for the Massachusetts Sociological Association," correspondence, notes, June 10-11, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 17)
    - Chronologisch Geordnetes Verzeichnis der Schriften von Max Weber, by unidentified author, memoranda, notes, 1979 (Box 112, Folder 18)
    - Growth of an Institution: The Chicago Real Estate Board, chapter IV, "Control and the Code," chapter VII, "The Roles of the Chicago Real Estate Board, The Policy and the Code," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 19)
    - Growth of an Institution: The Chicago Real Estate Board, "The Earmarks of an Institution," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 20)
    - "The Mendicant Salesman," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 21)
    - "The Executive Secretary," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 22)
    - "New Peoples," notes, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 23)
    - Foreword to Prescription for Leadership by Stephen J. Miller, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 24)
    - "Institutional Office and Personal Career," notes, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 25)
    - "Careers," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 26)
    - "Dilemmas and Contradictions of Status," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 27)
    - "Queries Concerning Industry and Society Growing Out of Study of Ethnic Relations in Industry," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 28)
    - Afterword to Profile of Catholic Colleges, by Andrew Greeley, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 29)
    - "Faculty and Administrators: Some Observations," n.d. (Box 112, Folder 30)
    - "Comment on Lieberson's Paper `How Can We Describe the Incidence and Distribution of Bilingualism?'" n.d. (Box 112, Folder 31)
  - Subseries 7: Publishing Correspondence
    - Chicago Real Estate Board, 1928-1929 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Barnes and Noble, 1935-1947 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of Hughes publications, 1943-1945, 1954 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Reviews of Hughes publications, 1946, 1960 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Publishing contracts, 1952-1963 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Where Peoples Meet, Free Press, reviews, 1953-1956 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - American Journal of Sociology Reader, 1958-1967 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - Man and His Work, Free Press, reviews, 1957-1959 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - French Canada in Transition, new paperback edition, manuscripts, 1962-1963 (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - Requests to reprint, 1962-1977 (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - "Desires and Needs of Society," reprint requests, 1963 (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1964 (Box 113, Folder 12)
    - Publicity, 1964-1968, 1976 (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - Requests for papers to be written, 1965-1967 (Box 113, Folder 14)
    - Making the Grade, proofs, 1968 (Box 113, Folder 15)
    - French Canada in Transition, 1968 (Box 113, Folder 16)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1968-1969 (Box 113, Folder 17)
    - Chicago Real Estate Board, Arno Press, memo, 1968-1980 (Box 113, Folder 18)
    - Royalty Statements, 1971-1979 (Box 113, Folder 19)
    - French Canada in Transition, 1972 edition, 1972-1974 (Box 113, Folder 20)
    - Greenwood Press, Inc., 1980 (Box 113, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 8: Publications
    - Book reviews, American Journal of Sociology, American Sociological Review, Comparative Studies, 1924-1965 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Book reviews, galleys, 1944-1950 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - Book reviews, 1951-1974 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - Reprints of articles and introductions, 1920s (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Reprints of articles and introductions, 1930s (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Reprints of articles and introductions, 1940s (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - Reprints of articles and introductions, 1950s (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - Hughes, Everett C., Buford H. Junker, Ray L. Gold, and Dorothy Kittel, Cases on Field Work, For Private Circulation Only, University of Chicago, October 1, 1952 (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - "How Colleges Differ," Planning College Policy for the Critical Decade Ahead (New York: College Entrance Examination Board, 1958) (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - Reprints of articles and introductions, 1960s (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Reprints of articles and introductions, 1970s (Box 115, Folder 2)
- Series V: French Canada Studies
  Series V, French Canada Studies, has been arranged into two subseries: (1) General,and (2) Study of the Careers and Career Aspirations of Young Canadians, 1965. The first subseries consists of notes, memoranda, papers by and about others in Canada, as well as collections of Canadian newspaper clippings from the early 1930s to the 1970s documenting topics such as French Canada during World War II. The arrangement of the files is chronological. These files were generated during the many visits to Canada Hughes made after he left in 1938 to teach at the University of Chicago. As can be seen from the material, Hughes closely watched the many manifestations of ethnic conflict between French and English speakers in Canada.
  Subseries 2, "Study of the Careers and Career Aspirations of Young Canadians, Some of French and Some of Other Backgrounds," was a study initiated by Canada's Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism with the additional support of McGill University and the UniversitÈ de MontrÈal. Hughes carried out his study in 1965. Students from both universities were recruited to assist in the field. The subseries has been subdivided into: administration and research data. The administrative material consists of correspondence with both administrators of the project and researchers. Project proposals, reports, studies of a similar nature, and memoranda by Hughes and the research team are in this group. The final report to the Commission, " Career Patterns of Young Montrealers in Certain White-Collar Occupations," was never published. This research data subseries contains the interviews done in the field by the project. They include interviews with individuals working in various professions carried out in 1965. They are arranged by profession or by corporation that defined profession such as Bell Telephone.
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Colonization, notes, newspaper clipping, 1927 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Mass marriage, Quebec, notes, photographs, 1939 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Drummondville, St. Hyacinthe fire, memoranda, January 1938 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Quebec diary, September 1942-March 1943 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, John Marshall, correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 115, Folder 7)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, John Marshall, Georges-Henri LÈvesque, correspondence, Hughes memoranda, report, 1943-1944 (Box 115, Folder 8)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Hughes memorandum, notes, 1943 (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Humanities Division, Conference of March 20-21, 1942, report, critical bibliography, New York, 1942 (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - "Action Catholique and Nationalism," mimeograph, ca. 1942 (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - Canada at War, Director of Public Information, Ottawa, pamphlets, news releases, 1941-1942 (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - Canada at War, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, 1940-1943 (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - Canada at War, notes, newspaper clippings, 1941-1942 (3) (Box 116, Folder 1-3)
    - Canada at War, free speech, newspaper clippings, tear sheets, 1939 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Canada at War, propaganda, newspaper clippings, 1940 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - French-Canada and the War, pamphlets, 1942-1944 (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - French-Canada and the War, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1940-1943 (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - French-Canada and the War, French-Canada is doing its part, conscription unnecessary, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - French-Canada and the War, youth at war, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - French-Canada and the War, women at war, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - French-Canada and the War, heritage and culture, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - French-Canada and the War, war heroes, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - French-Canada and the War, war work, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - French-Canada and the War, trials and misdemeanors, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 14)
    - French-Canada and the War, unity, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 15)
    - French-Canada and the War, Anglo-French ill will, notes, Canadian newspaper clippings, "War and French-English Relations in Canada," typescript, 1941 (Box 116, Folder 16)
    - French-Canada and the War, account of night in Drummondville to find deserters from the army, Canadian newspaper clippings, February 1945 (Box 116, Folder 17)
    - United States-Canada relations, "The relations between Canada and the United States...," manuscript, "Cultural Relations of Canada and the U.S.," by S. Delbert Clark, student paper, Hughes memoranda, notes, 1934-1939 (Box 116, Folder 18)
    - United States-Canada relations, visiting lectures in Illinois, correspondence, pamphlets, lecture notes, 1941-1942 (Box 116, Folder 19)
    - United States-Canada relations, The American Challenge by Jean-Jacques Servan-Schreiber, book review by Hughes, notes, newspaper clippings, 1968 (Box 116, Folder 20)
    - "Industrialization of Quebec," manuscript, notes, Quebec symposium [1952] (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Ralph Piddington, "A Genealogical Study of French-Canadian Kinship," mimeographed manuscript, 1957 (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - Jacques Brazeau, "Professor Jacques Brazeau on Quebec's Emerging Middle Class," Canadian Business, 1963 (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - New Movement, correspondence, notes, 1963 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Business, notes, ca. 1964 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Gerard Fortin, "Le Milieu Rural et son ...volution," mimeographed manuscript, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - Quebec's educational system, Margaret Westley, statistics, notes, memoranda, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Proposal for McGill University, correspondence, proposal, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - Clippings about Hughes, Montreal Gazette, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - Bi-lingualism vs. Unilingualism or Biculturalism vs. Uniculturalism, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - Changes in careers, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 11)